<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<livejournal>
<entry>
<itemid>10372</itemid>
<eventtime>2012-04-01 04:11:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2012-04-01 02:11:02</logtime>
<subject>LibreOffice goes money printing</subject>
<event>You may have heard the rumors already although there is nothing official yet: There is an exciting new idea making the rounds in LibreOffice circles. LibreOffice made and continues to make amazing progress pushing not only the product, but also the project as a whole to new levels. While the development of LibreOffice at the Document Foundation is widely supported by a diverse set of contributors and supporters from all over the world, there is always more we could do, if we had more time and money.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At least for the second problem, we are confident of having found the ultimate solution(*): We will just print whatever money we could use. Since &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostScript"&gt;PostScript&lt;/a&gt; is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the de facto standard to communicate layout to printers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and is turing-complete&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and most modern printers are actually rather capable computers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;we will use this to make printers generate a fraction of a &lt;a href="http://bitcoin.org/"&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; with every page that is printed. As modern printers have serious computation power the performance impact will hardly be noticeable to the end user.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, quite a few documents rarely ever get printed: They get distributed for consumption in formats like PDF (&lt;a href="http://blogs.computerworlduk.com/simon-says/2012/03/the-magic-of-editable-pdfs/index.htm"&gt;LibreOffice can generate those in an editable form, which is truely a great feature&lt;/a&gt;). To also tap into that potential resource, PDFs generated by LibreOffice will also inject a small Bitcoin generating implementation written in JavaScript, which will execute when the document is viewed with Software like Adobe Acrobat. Since -- in the light of cloud computing -- a lot of progress has been recently made in creating high-performance implementations of the carefully designed language that is JavaScript, we are confident that the Bitcoin generation in the background will hardly have any impact on the user experience for the viewer also in this case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are looking forward to complete the generation of a prototype for this at the&lt;a href="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Hackfest/Hamburg2012"&gt; Hackfest on April 14th/15th, 2012 in Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Hackfest/Hamburg2012"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="200" src="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/images/8/8e/HHHackfest.png" style="border-width: 0pt; border-style: solid;" width="714" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Now we recognize that while the generation of Bitcoins on printers and in document viewers is universally possible, there might be some environments (locked down corporate ones, for example) where transferring the coins as a donation to the benefit of the LibreOffice project might be problematic. To ensure these users are not left out in the cold when it comes to contributing back, we will leave our &lt;a href="http://www.libreoffice.org/get-involved/donate/"&gt;traditional donation page&lt;/a&gt; online even after this feature is introduced. &lt;a href="http://www.libreoffice.org/get-involved/donate/"&gt;Feel free to use it!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;(*) Although we cannot claim to be the sole originator of the idea: We took inspiration from central banks all over the world. &lt;/span&gt;</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>10514</itemid>
<eventtime>2012-04-16 19:43:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2012-04-16 17:43:55</logtime>
<subject>I survived LibreOffice Hackfest 2012 in Hamburg!</subject>
<event>The LibreOffice Hackfest 2012 in Hamburg was an exhausting, exciting and awesome experience. We started on Friday, 13th in the Schachcafe over some &lt;a href="http://www.lanedo.com/"&gt;Lanedo&lt;/a&gt; sponsored beer collecting all the Hackers flying in/riding in by train/returning from some downtown sightseeing. We also picked up some old StarDivision/Sun Developer hanging around by accident just there -- since all hackers are curious, the invitation to join us on the next day too was gladly accepted.&lt;br /&gt;Saturday started with a good breakfast and distributing the cool shirts that &lt;a href="http://www.Nerdshirt.de"&gt;Nerdshirt.de&lt;/a&gt; kindly sponsored us (Saturday also started with Thorsten kindly inviting me to speed up my steps to the event location for the amusement of the hackers already there -- over megaphone):&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/0000b7x8/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="480" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/0000b7x8/s640x480" style="border-width: 0pt; border-style: solid;" width="360" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The shirts, posters and pens quickly found their new owners once hackers were made aware of them -- and off we went for a session of full-throttle hackery. I practiced my skills as a jack of all trades, master of none and jumped from topic to topic:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;discussed bibisect/QA with Florian (remotely attending via Skype), &lt;a href="http://rrbd.wordpress.com/2012/04/14/hackfest-hamburg-2012/"&gt;Rainer&lt;/a&gt;, Friedrich and Rob, &lt;a href="http://flosmind.wordpress.com/2012/04/16/bisecting-libreoffice-youtube-now-with-subtitles/"&gt;resulting in this awesome screencast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simplifying login and authentication on TDF services with Mike and the infrastructure guys (OpenID should be the way to go)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;some cross compile gbuild tweaking with Eilidh&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;how branching works in git with Christina&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moggi kindly reminding me that when I joined the project, everyone had to be nice to me because only I knew how gbuild worked, but now we have so many with a deep knowledge about it (Norbert, Matus, Michael Stahl, David to name a few) that I am replaceable -- somewhat uncomforting that, I should have made gbuild more write-only&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Earned myself two Windows configure bugs by Regina&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating tasty pasta prepared by Italo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;discussed Ubuntu ppa strategy with Mike&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;discussed gerrit progress with Robert and Norbert (attending remotely -- the volunteer that never sleeps)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;proved with Tor that both of us together qualify as a four year old preschooler by solving a riddle that kids solve easily while adults struggle (kendy proved that he qualifies alone, while moggi disqualified himself as a preschooler -- his higher math education proved to be a real handicap)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;jumped in for a few minutes to give hints to Andreas on how to edit the PDF export dialog&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;lots of other topics ...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Saturday ended with a sip of bavarian single malt whiskey (which tasted better than it sounds: it got a &amp;quot;not too terrible&amp;quot; by a scottish native and no outright dismissing by a trained grappa tester) at 4am local time. Then I returned back home with now three couchsurfers (I won Robert in addition, as we discussed gerrit to late for him to possibly return to his reserved couch). Sunday continued with what began on Saturday. We managed to lure some of the remaining hackers into the sunlight with promises of fortune and fame:&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/0000cxgb/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="426" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/0000cxgb/s640x480" style="border-width: 0pt; border-style: solid;" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;as you can see some of the sponsored black shirts with the hacker glider are already worn right there.&lt;br /&gt;As things got calmer, because more and more hackers returned home, I managed to focus myself on one topic and implemented an small idea proposed to me by Tor: &lt;a href="http://nabble.documentfoundation.org/per-library-debug-builds-now-possible-via-configure-td3914016.html"&gt;Per Library debug builds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;(for more, see also: &lt;a href="http://blog.thebehrens.net/2012/04/16/libreoffice-hamburg-hackfest-2012/"&gt;Thorstens post and all the others linked in there&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>10977</itemid>
<eventtime>2012-04-18 12:37:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2012-04-18 10:37:18</logtime>
<subject>State and Overview of LibreOffice Ubuntu Packages</subject>
<event>&lt;div style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Come together, yeah&lt;br /&gt;Come together, yeah&lt;br /&gt;Come together, yeah&lt;br /&gt;Come together, yeah&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;-- the Beatles, Come Together&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here is a short update on the state of LibreOffice Packaging on Ubuntu (and Debian):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/precise"&gt;Ubuntu 12.04 LTS (Precise)&lt;/a&gt; will ship with at least &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/precise/+source/libreoffice"&gt;LibreOffice 3.5.2-2ubuntu1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thanks to the great work of &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ricotz"&gt;ricotz&lt;/a&gt;, LibreOffice 3.5.2 is also available for &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/ppa/+sourcepub/2375289/+listing-archive-extra"&gt;Ubuntu 11.10 (Oneiric)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/ppa/+sourcepub/2375288/+listing-archive-extra"&gt;Ubuntu 10.04 LTS (Lucid)&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/ppa"&gt;LibreOffice PPA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There is a &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/libreoffice-3-4"&gt;new PPA for the LibreOffice 3.4 series&lt;/a&gt;. It contains the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/libreoffice-3-4/+sourcepub/2378562/+listing-archive-extra"&gt;latest minor release (3.4.6)&lt;/a&gt; of LibreOffice 3.4. From now on there will be a PPA for each LibreOffice major series (3.4, 3.5, 3.6) allowing users to update to the latest minor release of that series, without having to wait for the thorough process of &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/StableReleaseUpdates"&gt;Stable Release Update&lt;/a&gt; verification. There will never be a surprise update to the next major release in these PPAs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;During the 3.4/3.5 upstream releases, Debian (and thus Ubuntu) switched from building with the old &lt;a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/build"&gt;libreoffice-build wrapper&lt;/a&gt; to a clean direct build. All patches had to be either upstreamed or migrated from libreoffice-build to our own vendor-patches. This is a lot of thankless work (as it risks regressions, while nothing changes if everyting goes well). A quick &amp;quot;git log&amp;quot; against the LibreOffice packaging repository from the 3.4.1-1 release to now (3.5.2) shows more than 800 commits -- over 600 of those by Rene Engelhard, but also including contributions by Lionel Elie Mamane, Nelson A. de Oliveira, Rico Tzschichholz, Lubok Lunak.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These changes have made Ubuntu and Debian come a lot closer to upstream -- a lot of patches have been either removed as obsolete, upstreamed to LibreOffice or included as vendor-patches. With &lt;a href="http://anonscm.debian.org/gitweb/?p=pkg-openoffice/libreoffice.git;a=tree;f=patches;h=549a0141f723ef3c3b285ab97561b3e3e7961e64;hb=83cdc913d0d3c5d93ede9b0b41995afc908d729c"&gt;only 41 Patches in debian/patches&lt;/a&gt; we are a lot closer to upstream now, which is very good as it removes the need to doublecheck bugs to be Debian/Ubuntu-specific in the most cases. Of the five patches that are only in Ubuntu, but not in Debian:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;three are minor fixes that have been upstreamed to LibreOffice 3.6 (but are not backported to 3.5 there)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;two are backported upstream patches from LibreOffice 3.5.3 so they are in the LTS release from the start&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;This shows that a lot of friction in upstreaming patches has been removed -- and whatever we are patching in can and is upstreamed quickly to Debian or LibreOffice, keeping our vendor patch queue small. Thanks to everyone who made this possible -- most of all: Rene Engelhard.</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>11119</itemid>
<eventtime>2012-04-28 16:47:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2012-04-28 14:47:50</logtime>
<subject>Ubuntu 12.04 LTS (Precise Pangolin) released with LibreOffice 3.5.2, forward to 3.6 with bibisect!</subject>
<event>&lt;div style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;I was so much older then,&lt;br /&gt;Im younger than that now.&lt;br /&gt;-- My Back Pages, Bob Dylan&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Ubuntu release day is over and it ships with &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/precise/+source/libreoffice"&gt;LibreOffice 3.5.2&lt;/a&gt; -- the best free office suite ever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="289" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/0000dzcp" style="border-width: 0pt; border-style: solid;" width="500" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A big Thank You to everyone who contributed to make that possible: LibreOffice developers, bugwranglers, testers, translators, documentation writers, infrastructure admins, packagers, event organizers, administrative gremlins and everyone I forgot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the best &amp;quot;the king is dead, long live the king&amp;quot;-fashion, lets look forward to a great LibreOffice 3.6.X series which will be on the next Ubuntu release named &lt;a href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/1121"&gt;Quantal Quetzal&lt;/a&gt;. And here is a piece to keep us moving quickly and confidently: &lt;a href="http://people.canonical.com/~bjoern/bibisect-3.6-20120328.tar.xz"&gt;a first bibisect archive of LibreOffice 3.6/master&lt;/a&gt;. See &lt;a href="https://wiki.documentfoundation.org/index.php?title=QA/HowToBibisect"&gt;&amp;quot;How to Bibisect&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SA88flop4MM"&gt;Florians excellent video&lt;/a&gt; for what to do with it -- the only change is that this bibisect needs Ubuntu 12.04 (precise) instead of Ubuntu 11.10 (oneiric) now. I will provide updates for this bibisect along as we approach the LibreOffice 3.6 release.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bibisect already proved very helpful in triaging and preventing regressions in LibreOffice 3.5 -- in LibreOffice 3.6, we will be able to even better control the quality and pinpoint problems, since we have bibisect-3.6 continuing right were bibisect-3.5 ended: At the start of the LibreOffice 3.5 release branch. This will give us an enormous practical advantage in quickly identifing and fixing issues in our huge codebase -- without the highly intrusive encumbrance and overhead that the dogmatic classic approaches to QA enforce and burden projects with(*).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(*) We implement those too, but are only tightening them on the release branches.&lt;/div&gt;</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
</livejournal>