<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<livejournal>
<entry>
<itemid>857</itemid>
<eventtime>2011-05-02 13:22:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2011-05-02 11:21:57</logtime>
<subject>LibreOffice on Ubuntu 11.04 'Natty Narwhal'</subject>
<event>Ubuntu 11.04 'Natty Narwhal'&amp;nbsp; has been released on April 28th, 2011 and is the first Ubuntu release to contain a LibreOffice in the default install.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00001h6k/"&gt;&lt;img border="0" height="200" width="320" alt="" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00001h6k/s320x240" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A few days after the official release, it indeed seems to be a overall smooth transition. Apart from the move from OpenOffice.org to LibreOffice, there are some other exciting changes in this Ubuntu release: The LibreOffice icons are not only used in LibreOffice itself, but also on the dash and in the default theme for Nautilus. So the new icons are consistently being used in the whole desktop experience. Congratulations to the LibreOffice Design team for this success!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, by installing the &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/lo-menubar"&gt;lo-menubar package&lt;/a&gt; you can already enable the &lt;a href="http://aruiz.synaptia.net/siliconisland/2011/02/introducing-libreoffice-integration-with-unitys-application-menubar.html"&gt;LibreOffice Integration with Unity that was created by Alberto Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;. The code for this feature has already been &lt;a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/libs-core/tree/framework/source/lomenubar"&gt;upstreamed to LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt; and is also on the 3.4 branch and thus will be part of upcoming releases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So: Where do we go from here? Work on &lt;a href="http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/646"&gt;Ubuntu 11.10 'Oneiric Ocelot&lt;/a&gt;' is starting right now. In fact, the first fixes to critical issues related to LibreOffice have &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/hunspell-en-us/+bug/773646"&gt;already been released&lt;/a&gt;. More to come soon!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A great thanks to all who make these awesome developments possible and a special thanks to Rene Engelhard for his hard work on debian packaging.</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>1172</itemid>
<eventtime>2011-05-18 14:33:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2011-05-18 12:33:32</logtime>
<subject>LibreOffice at the Ubuntu Developer Summit 2011 in Budapest</subject>
<event>This has been my first &lt;a href="http://uds.ubuntu.com/"&gt;Ubuntu Developer Summit&lt;/a&gt; and therefore also my first chance to meet up with the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~canonical-desktop-team/+mugshots"&gt;Canonical Desktop Team&lt;/a&gt; in person. I had been warned before that UDS is an exciting, exhausting, enlightening and inspiring experience and I was not disappointed on any of these points. The &lt;a href="http://summit.ubuntu.com/uds-o/"&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; is just mindblowing, the &lt;a href="http://www.corinthia.com/en/Budapest/home/"&gt;location&lt;/a&gt; was great, even though little was seen from the outside world, because there was always something that needed urgent discussion. Luckily I have been in Budapest last year already for the last (in every meaning of the word, it seems) OOoCon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I drafted two blueprints about LibreOffice which were discussed in sessions on Wednesday:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blueprints.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+spec/desktop-o-libreoffice-packaging"&gt;&lt;span id="yui_3_3_0_1_130572099237631" class="yui3-editable_text-text"&gt;LibreOffice Packaging for Oneiric&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="yui3-editable_text-text"&gt; &lt;a href="http://summit.ubuntu.com/uds-o/meeting/desktop-o-libreoffice-packaging/"&gt;(session notes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blueprints.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+spec/desktop-o-libreoffice-communities"&gt;&lt;span id="yui_3_3_0_1_130572099887631" class="yui3-editable_text-text"&gt;Connect LibreOffice Communities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://summit.ubuntu.com/uds-o/meeting/desktop-o-libreoffice-communities/"&gt; (session notes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;It was also great to able to have a nice short chat with &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~alberto.ruiz"&gt;Alberto Ruiz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ted"&gt;Ted Gould&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href="http://sweetshark.livejournal.com/857.html"&gt;LibreOffice Unity integration&lt;/a&gt; and finally also meet other contributors to the LibreOffice project (for example: &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~vish"&gt;Vish&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~kami911"&gt;KAMI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~evfool"&gt;Robert Roth&lt;/a&gt;) and members of the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~jwcampbell"&gt;Ubuntu Documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~dpm"&gt;Translation&lt;/a&gt; teams with an interest in LibreOffice and its place on the desktop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On a side note: My flight there was delayed, making me miss my connecting flight, but that allowed me flighting through the dusk, which is always so beautiful, that I would like to share a view of that with you:&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00003gtd/"&gt;&lt;img width="160" height="240" border="0" align="middle" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00003gtd/s320x240" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>1550</itemid>
<eventtime>2011-05-19 19:49:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2011-05-19 18:04:17</logtime>
<subject>Back To The Future -- LibreOffice 4.0 API</subject>
<event>&lt;div style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marty McFly: Wait a minute, Doc. Ah... Are you telling me that you built a time machine... out of a DeLorean?  &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Emmett Brown: The way I see it, if you're gonna build a time machine into a car, why not do it with some style?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Following this &lt;a href="http://nabble.documentfoundation.org/Proposing-a-new-Easy-Hack-project-consistent-namespaces-td2826117.html"&gt;lively discussion&lt;/a&gt; on the developer mailing list, we came to the conclusion that we need a wiki page to collect all the stuff we would like to change, but can not now, because it would make us to brutally incompatible. This is:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;not because we want to change everything right now and break existing client of the API.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;also not because we never want to change the API and just want to postpone this topic ad infinitum.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;It is because a change in API is something very painful for the clients and thus should not be done incrementally, because then the API will always be broken for somebody then -- making everyone losing their trust. So a change in API has to be a very rare and big event: it has to be one deep quick cut.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/LibreOffice4"&gt;The LibreOffice4 wiki page&lt;/a&gt; is there to prepare for this: Once we decide to go that way, we should have all the brainstorms, discussions and flamewars behind us. Once we decide to go that way, we will have a clear vision of the benefits and drawbacks of the changes and will be excited to make the move. Up until then however, nothing will break the API. It will take a lot of time and work to get to that point where the step will be the right thing to do, but right now you can help us by proposing ideas there and discuss the proposals by others to make LibreOffice better in a big way.&lt;br /&gt;</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
<entry>
<itemid>1858</itemid>
<eventtime>2011-05-20 15:31:00</eventtime>
<logtime>2011-05-20 13:36:14</logtime>
<subject>One-click compiling (LibreOffice on Ubuntu)</subject>
<event>Wouldnt it be nice to have one-click compiles of LibreOffice on Ubuntu? Fret no more, good times are here!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But before we get to that, here are a few general hints on how to build LibreOffice 3.4.X and the LibreOffice master branch on Ubuntu:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;please use the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/ppa/+sourcepub/1733537/+listing-archive-extra"&gt;make-dfsg_3.81-8ubuntu2~ppa1&lt;/a&gt; package available at the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~libreoffice/+archive/ppa/+sourcepub/1733537/+listing-archive-extra"&gt;LibreOffice Packaging PPA&lt;/a&gt;. It contains the backport of a fix to GNU make which has not yet made it into the Ubuntu/Debian main Repositories. Without it, you likely see make SEGV on large projects -- esp. tail_build.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Because of Junit on Ubuntu/Debian excluding Hamcrest, &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/junit/+bug/784631"&gt;you will need to manually download a full junit package&lt;/a&gt;. Here is the upstream link: &lt;a href="https://github.com/downloads/KentBeck/junit/junit-4.9b2.jar"&gt;https://github.com/downloads/KentBeck/junit/junit-4.9b2.jar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;For 3.4 you currently need to cherrypick &lt;a rel="nofollow" target="_top" href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/bootstrap/commit/?id=33b25c9c7ac5c960991c71d641740dbc8fa432b5"&gt;33b25c9c7ac5c960991c71d641740dbc8fa432b5&lt;/a&gt; from bootstrap on master until that is reviewed for the branch.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;And if you are fearless(*), run these commands (which already take care of the Junit and cherrypicking stuff themselves):&lt;div style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: smaller;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;sudo apt-get build-dep libreoffice&lt;br /&gt;sudo apt-get install git ccache&lt;br /&gt;wget http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/contrib/dev-tools/plain/ubuntu-jenkins/setup-ubuntu-jenkins.sh -O - |sh -&lt;br /&gt;java -jar ~/.jenkins/jenkins.war&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;and point your browser to: &lt;a href="http://localhost:8080"&gt;http://localhost:8080&lt;/a&gt; and you will find something like this:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00004x8c/"&gt;&lt;img width="188" height="240" border="0" align="middle" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/sweetshark/pic/00004x8c/s320x240" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;Click on &amp;quot;schedule a build&amp;quot; on the right side for ccache, tarfiles and repo-mirror once to get setup. If those are finished, by &amp;quot;scheduling a build&amp;quot; for libreoffice-3-4 or libreoffice-master you can build and test the current release branch and the master branch as often as you want to with just one click. What are the advantages of this?&lt;br /&gt;Here are some:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You have a reproducable build setup.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can completely mess up you checkout without needing a very slow redownload from freedesktop.org.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can schedule multiple builds in a row.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your new and old build logs are managed automatically -- if something breaks you can be sure which one was the last good build for you.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can trigger builds by various means automatically. For example, you can let Jenkins make a build when you get up and see immediately if somebody broke the master for you in the morning when you start working.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Plugins"&gt;Jenkins is very extensible.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;A lot more will be possible with &lt;a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/libreoffice/contrib/dev-tools/tree/onegit/README"&gt;one git&lt;/a&gt; and this is just a proof-of-concept, but still it might be quite useful to some already. So, comment and ideas (and most of all: patches and commits) on how to improve this are most welcome!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: smaller;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(*) In general, it is not advisable to pipe some random file from the Internet to your shell. Also take care that port 8080 is reasonably secured on you machine before starting Jenkins.Caveat Emptor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;For the repository synchronization script you currently need Python 2.7. Sorry about that, I will try to get rid of that dependency soon.</event>
<security>public</security>
<allowmask>0</allowmask>
<current_music/>
<current_mood/>
</entry>
</livejournal>